<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-12T06:34:34+05:30</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">My Site</title><subtitle>Jekyll version of the Massively theme by HTML5UP</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My hands on experience</title><link href="/blog/My-hands-on-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My hands on experience" /><published>2018-06-12T06:34:16+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-12T06:34:16+05:30</updated><id>/blog/My-hands-on-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/My-hands-on-experience/">&lt;p&gt;This was surely a very useful course, but it wasn’t enough to start solving problems based on ML.
 The course taught me the mathematical aspects of Machine Learning very well, it began with the explaination of Linear Regression (single variable), under which it covered hypothesis, cost function and gradient descent algorithm. Then it explained multiple variable Linear Regression covering feature scaling, learning rate, decison boundary etc.This was followed by Logistic Regression. 
 After that the problems based on overfitting and underfitting were explained, how they could be identified and resolved.Then, Neural Networks, Model Selection, Regularization, high bias and variance, error hypothesis, Support Vector Machines (SVM), Clustering, Data Compression, PCA and in the end Recommender System was discussed in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this course was all about maths, I wanted to learn how to implement mathematical functions in python, and the only way to do this is to practice questions based on real data sets. This is time consuming, but this is the only way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">This was surely a very useful course, but it wasn’t enough to start solving problems based on ML.
 The course taught me the mathematical aspects of Machine Learning very well, it began with the explaination of Linear Regression (single variable), under which it covered hypothesis, cost function and gradient descent algorithm. Then it explained multiple variable Linear Regression covering feature scaling, learning rate, decison boundary etc.This was followed by Logistic Regression. 
 After that the problems based on overfitting and underfitting were explained, how they could be identified and resolved.Then, Neural Networks, Model Selection, Regularization, high bias and variance, error hypothesis, Support Vector Machines (SVM), Clustering, Data Compression, PCA and in the end Recommender System was discussed in detail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First year done right !</title><link href="/blog/My-Intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First year done right !" /><published>2018-06-12T06:19:16+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-12T06:19:16+05:30</updated><id>/blog/My-Intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/My-Intro/">&lt;p&gt;My first year in Kgp was perfect. Be it enjoying life to the fullest or exploring my interests, it was a wonderful experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the beginning of a new life here. The lifestyle was different and people were all new, so it took me some time to get adjusted to the culture of Kgp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning it was all about meeting new people, making new friends, exploring the campus and most importantly becoming part of societies. I joined Business Club in my first semester and KOSS in the second semester. I learnt a lot from both the societies and also got a chance to meet some wonderful seniors there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a member of KOSS I had to complete a task of making my own website using jekyll. It was not that easy for me because I did not know anything about jekyll. But with the help of some documentations I was able to set up my own jekyll based portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">My first year in Kgp was perfect. Be it enjoying life to the fullest or exploring my interests, it was a wonderful experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why did I dive into these courses?</title><link href="/blog/My-Interest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why did I dive into these courses?" /><published>2018-06-12T04:46:16+05:30</published><updated>2018-06-12T04:46:16+05:30</updated><id>/blog/My-Interest</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/My-Interest/">&lt;p&gt;After my end sems were over I was scratching my head about what am I going to do for the next two and a half months? I knew that I have to work on my coding skills and Python was the very first thing that came to my mind at that time. But what else? How am I going to utilize my summers? How do I figure out the things that interests me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I realized I’ll have to start somewhere. So I started googling about random things to know more about them. I googled about Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Structures, Algorithms, etc.Then,I started the course on Machine Learning from coursera.It kind of fascinated me because there were no prerequisites. It didn’t require any hard core coding skills or any strong mathematical background, just a basic knowledge of calculus and linear algebra was all that was needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course helped me to understand what exactly machine learning is and what are its applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">After my end sems were over I was scratching my head about what am I going to do for the next two and a half months? I knew that I have to work on my coding skills and Python was the very first thing that came to my mind at that time. But what else? How am I going to utilize my summers? How do I figure out the things that interests me?</summary></entry></feed>
